in this video we are going to learn how
hackers can steal your information and
Inspire on everything you're typing on
your keyboard just by using zoom and a
little bit of AI that is according to a
new paper called a practical deep
learning based acoustic side Channel
attack on keyboards in this paper a team
of researchers explain how they were
able to train a deep learning model that
can know what you are typing on your
keyboard based on the sound your
keystrokes make with 95 accuracy this is
known as a side a Channel attack side
Channel attacks or scas are attacks that
don't break the security of your machine
instead they make use of the side
information or signals that your
computer emits normally signals like
power usage hit or sound like on the
attack we're talking about this kind of
attack an acoustic attack has been
around for a while it is not new what is
new is how accurate it is thanks to AI
we'll know we should use long and secure
password and we should cover the screen
or keyboard when we are writing a
password in a public place but if you
think about it we do very little to
obfuscate the sound of our keyboard some
people even try to make their keyboard
even louder maybe after this attack we
will all have to start talking very
loudly or playing music while writing
our password if you're thinking this
kind of attack can only happen to those
people that use mechanical keyboard that
have very loud and special sounds you
will be wrong the laptop used on this
paper to demonstrate the attacks is
actually a MacBook Pro which is not a
loud keyboard at all the way the attack
works is very simple but interesting
first hackers will have to record the
keystrokes of the victim's keyboard you
might think this is hard to do maybe
they will have to hack the phone of the
victim first to access the microphone or
even easier they can just invite the
victim to hop on a zoom meeting and
correlate the messages written on the
chat window with the keyboard sounds
picked up by the microphone or they can
build a dodgy website that requests
access to the camera and microphone and
if the victim gives permission then it's
over after they know how your keyboard
sounds like the hackers will need to
isolate those sounds here is an image
from the paper that shows us how the
keystroke sounds can be isolated from
other sounds using energy thresholds
then the attackers will have to take
those isolated keystroke sounds and turn
them into male spectrograms which are a
modified version of a spectrogram
spectrograms are a visual representation
of audio they are a plane of colored
pixels with an X and Y axis the x-axis
represents time the y-axis represents
the frequency and the brightness of the
pixel represents the loudness of the
sound on this image we can see the
waveform and the male spectrogram of a
keystroke recorded using a microphone
and another one recorded through soon
with the sounds turned into images the
next step of the attack is to train a
neural network with those images the
theme behind this paper chose to use
coat it an image classifier model built
by Google's Brain theme this classifier
achieved an accuracy of 95 percent with
keystroke sounds recorded by an iPhone
13 mini placed 17 centimeters away from
the laptop it achieved 93 accuracy with
keystroke sounds recorded on a zoom call
and it achieved 91.7 accuracy by just
calling the victim through Skype scary
to protect ourselves against this attack
the team of researchers behind this
paper suggest a couple of things first
they suggest a typing using touch typing
just by doing this the keystroke
recognition was reduced from 64 to 40
another mitigation technique is to use
passwords that have both lower and
uppercase and of course finally the
authors of the paper recommend playing
sounds while writing our passwords
preferably sounds with fake keystrokes
rather than white noise or other sounds
since they are fairly easy to isolate
and of course they reckon comment you
mute your microphone when writing on
your keyboard what a crazy word we live
in thanks to AI attacks that were not
easy to perform are going to become
trivial to do more and more I hope you
enjoyed this video if you did please
consider leaving a like and subscribing
to the channel just two clicks it's for
free but it helps me a lot and let me
know what you think write your opinion
on the comments if you like the way I
explain Concepts and you would like to
learn things like JavaScript python
react react native go Dart flutter among
many others by building real life
products and skipping the boring Theory
all for free all you have to do is click
the link below to join any of our many
free courses that you can take right now
for absolutely free with me click the
link below and I will see you then
see you on the next one bye
thank you